Register of the Vrangel' collection
Hoover Institution Archives
- Part II: Bound volumes (Boxes 136-161)
  - Political correspondence, Vol. I; Baron P. Vrangel'; P. Krasnov, including interview; Lieut.-Gen. A. Bogaevskii; V. Burtsev; Ob"edinennyi Sovet Dona, Kubani i Tereka; M. Bernatskii; Lieut.-Gen. E. Miller; Lieut.-Gen. P. Makhrov; P. Struve; Lieut.-Gen. I. KHolmnsen; Lieut.-Gen. A. von Lampe; Lieut.-Gen. P. SHatilov; N. Savin; A. Guchkov; D. Grimm; Gen. Podtiagin; S. Il'in... B. Savinkov (Russkii Evakuatsionnyi Komitet v Pol'she): report to French government, also other material re situation of Russian Army and refugees in Poland and correspondence with Baron P. Vrangel'; report re position and composition of Third Army, Army of Maj.-Gen. S. Bulak-Balakhovich and Armiia Ukrainskoi Narodnoi Respubliki; "Polozhenie o Russkom Delovom Kabinete v Parizhe"; miscellaneous material re Cossacks, including Astrakhanskoe Kazach'e Voisko, Kalmytskaia CHast'; Politicheskaia CHast' pri Glavnokomanduiushchem R.A.; Paris, A. Guchkov: reports re political situation, including internal politics of emigre circles and relations with foreign governments; Politicheskii Ob"edinennyi Komitet and P. IUrenev: correspondence and "Otkrytoe pis'mo k obshchestvennomu mneniiu Evropy i Ameriki"; Lieut.-Gen. P. SHatilov: circular letter re situation of Russian Army; Rossiiskii Zemsko-Gorodskoi Komitet Pomoshchi Bezhentsam: "Obshchiia Polozheniia" and correspondence S. KHripunov and V. Zeeler; Ataman Semenov: "Appel aux Peuple du Monde" and "K Narodam Rossii i k Russkim Liudiam," printed leaflets, also correspondence with Baron P. Vrangel' and miscellaneous other material re situation in the Far East; Rossiiskii Finansovo-Promyshlenno-Torgoyi Soiuz; S"ezd Russkago Natsional'nago Ob"edineniia: miscellaneous material, including correspondence of A. Kartashev; miscellaneous material Russian Navy; greetings addressed to Baron P. Vrangel' by emigre organizations; petition to Baron P. Vrangel' from paricipants of Kronstadt Rebellion (1921); typescript, handwritten and printed matter, November 1, 1920-July 29, 1921 (Box 148, File File 36)
    Available on microfilm reel 192
  - Political correspondence, Vol. II; Baron P. Vrangel'; Lieut.-Gen. E. Miller (includes report re B. Savinkov and information re N. Sokolov's investigation of death of Imperial Family); Lieut.-Gen. A. von Lampe; Lieut.-Gen. A. Lukomskii (includes copy of original report re murder of Imperial Family made by eyewitness first arriving at scene, Esaul Tiaguntsov, also report: "Russkaia Armiia na chuzhbine"); A. Guchkov, including reports re political situation; P. Krasnov; S. Il'in (including letter to A. Dulles, American Embassy in Constantinople); Lieut.-Gen. P. SHatilov; V. SHtrandtman; Lieut.-Gen. I. KHolmnsen (includes information re situation of emigres in Germany); P. Struve; Lieut.-Gen. A. Bogaevskii (includes material re relationship of Baron P. Vrangel' to cossack forces); D. Grimm (includes report re Kronstadt sailors); A. Polunin: report re Nansen-CHicherin agreement; B. Bakhmetev; Mitropolit Antonii, Kievskii i Galitskii (re church sobor); S. Paleolog; V. Nikol'skii; A. Amfiteatrov; A. Kartashev; Lieut.-Gen. P. Glazenap; A. Trepov; N. Savin; greetings addressed to Baron P. Vrangel' by emigre organizations... "Zaiavlenie Generala Vrangelia," printed leaflet; Russkoe Zagranichnoe TSerkovnoe Sobranie, Sremski Karlovci: list of participants, report of N. L'vov and other miscellaneous material; League of Nations: "Memorandum po voprosu o russkikh bezhentsakh," F. Nansen and other material dealing with Russian refugees; "Ko vsemm russkim soldatam...," re Gen. Slashchev-Krymskii; "Ot Russkago Natsional'nago Komiteta, Russkago Parlamentskago Komiteta i Sobraniia Zemskikh i Gorodskikh Glasnykh v Parizhe," re Cannes Conference; typescript and handwritten, July 28, 1921-February 23, 1922, January 1922 (File File 37)
    Available on microfilm reel 193
  - Political correspondence, Vol. III; Baron P. Vrangel'; S. Il'in; N. Savich: report re Russian Navy (Dobrovol'cheskii Flot); A. Guchkov, including reports re political situation; Bezpartiinaia Konferentsiia Russkikh Rabochikh: report; Lieut.-Gen. E. Miller; A. Trepov; G. Glinka; P. Krupenskii; I. Nazhivin; Lieut.-Gen. A. von Lampe; A. Tyrkova-Williams; A. Kartashev: "Vpechatlenie o Poezdke v Gallipoli," lecture delivered to Londonskii Otdel Natsional'nago Soiuza and also correspondence; N. CHebyshev; E. Demidov; Prince G. Leikhtenbergskii; Russian civic organizations in Paris, including Parlamentskii Komitet: letter to Secretary of State of U.S.; Lieut.-Gen. P. SHatilov; Lieut.-Gen. I. KHolmnsen, includes reports re political groups; N. Markov and Vysshii Monarkhicheskii Sovet: miscellaneous material; P. Makhrov; Konferentsiia Russkago narodno-monarkhicheskago Soiuza miscellaneous material; Mitropolit Evlogii, "Zavedyvaiushchii russkimi pravoslavnymi TSerkvami zagranitsei"; E. Sablin; I. Aleksinskii... Sovet Nitstskago Monarkhicheskago Obshchestva: minutes of meetings; N. Tretiakov; TSentral'nyi Komitet Belorusskikh...organizatsii; IU. Savinkov; Hungary: V. SHtrandtman and Esaul Ilovaiskii (Russian Military Agent in Budapest) includes miscellaneous material re Kalmyks, Astrakhan Cossacks, Prince Tundutov and L. Kazem Bek (Monarchist Union of Hungary); V. Burtsev and Obshchee Delo, including financial matters; D. Grimm; Soedinennoe Biuro Zemskikh i Gorodskikh glasnykh v Konstantinopole: report re Russian refugees in Constantinople; greetings addressed to Baron P. Vrangel'; IU. Danilov; typescript and handwritten, February 6-August 24, 1922 (Box 149, File File 38)
    Available on microfilm reel 194
  - Political correspondence, Vol. IV; Baron. P. Vrangel'; S. Il'in, including report re Russkii Sovet; I. Aleksinskii; Vsezagranichnyi TSerkovnyi Sobor, Sremski Karlovci, miscellaneous material; V. Burtsev and Obshchee Delo; Vysshii Monarkhicheskii Sovet, including material re "CHrezvychainoe Zasedanie," Paris,; miscellaneous material... A. Trepov; Russkii Natsional'nyi Komitet, Paris: open letters, resolutions and other miscellaneous material; Lieut.-Gen. I. KHolmnsen, includes material re relationship with American press; S. Paleolog; IU. Danilov; Lieut.-Gen. A. von Lampe; protests of Don, Kuban and Terek Cossacks against F. Nansen repatriation plan; report: "Amerikantsy o Rossii"; P. Krasnov; I. Aleksinskii; B. Brazol, report: "Deiatel'nost' Russkikh Monarkhicheskikh Organizatsii v S.SH.A."; IU. Lodyzhenskii and Rossiiskoe Obshchestvo Krasnago Kresta; Mitropolit Evlogii; Lieut.-Gen. E. Miller, including financial matters; A. Neratov; report re activity of A. Bakhmetev; A. Savich; V. SHtrandtman; A. Guchkov; A. IUgorskii, "Ocherednaia Zadacha Russkago Natsional'nago Dvizheniia"; A. Kartashev; Mezhdunarodnoe Biuro Truda: report re Russian refugees; report re Bolshevik take-over of Vladivostok: "V Osoboe Soveshchanie Rossiiskago Obshchestva Krasnago Kresta na D/Vostoke"; A. KHripunov; Soveshchanie Predstavitelei Russkikh Obshchestvennykh Organizatsii v Sofii: protocol; Russkii Komitet v Turtsii: open letter, printed copy; Italy: miscellaneous material re contacts with Fascist circles; M. Girs, including financial matters, especially Russian monies held by Bulgarian government; Zemsko-Gorodskoi Soiuz (Zemgor), miscellaneous material; typescript and handwritten, August 25, 1922-July 7, 1923, November 1922 (Box 149A., File File 39)
    Available on microfilm reel 195
  - Political correspondence, Vol. V; Baron P. Vrangel'; Lieut.-Gen. A. von Lampe, including "Zapiska ob otnoshenii russkikh pravykh monarkhicheskikh organizatsii k russkoi armii"; A. Ladyzhenskii; S. Paleolog; A. Guchkov; D. Grimm; Lieut.-Gen. E.Klimovich, secret report: "Proekt platformy soiuza respublikanskikh-demokraticheskikh organizatsii"... Soiuz Russkikh Ofitserov...v...S.KH.S.," address to Baron P. Vrangel'; N. Tal'berg; N. CHebyshev; P. Krasnov; A. Trepov; P. Skarzhinskii; V. Burtsev; Lieut.-Gen. P. SHatilov; I. Aleksinskii and Russkii Komitet v Turtsii; I. Il'in: political project; M. Girs; Germany (Bavaria): miscellaneous material re relationship of Russian emigre community (Gen. V. Biskupskii) to political situation; lists of recipients of "Gallipoli Album"; I. Il'in: transcript of lecture, "Gosudarstvennyi smysl Beloi Armii" and correspondence; Vysshii Monarkhicheskii Sovet: report re trip through Balkans and Bessarabia and other material; A. Kartashev and Russkii Natsional'nyi Komitet; V. Nikol'skii; Lieut.-Gen. M. Fostikov; V. Gurko; V. SHul'gin; E. Sablin; IU. Danilov; N. Savich; Delegatskoe Sobranie Narodno-Monarkhicheskago Soiuza, miscellaneous material; Lieut.-Gen. I. KHolmnsen: reports re attempts to create emigre union in Paris; B. Ivanitskii and Rosiiskoe Obshchestvo Krasnago Kresta... P. Miliukov, transcript of lecture: "O Belom Dvizhenii"; V. Burtsev and Obshchee Delo; A. Tyrkova-Williams; A. KHripunov; P. Dolgorukov: report re his attempted penetration into Soviet Union; Soiuz Russkikh Ofitserov Uchastnikov Velikoi Voiny, printed open letter; Gen. N. Baratov and Soiuz Russkikh Invalidov; Mitropolit Antonii: "Poslanie k Russkoi armii..."; typescript and handwritten, July 20, 1923-January 8, 1925 (Box 150, File File 40)
    Available on microfilm reel 197
  - Political correspondence, Vol. VI; Baron P. Vrangel', includes printed leaflet: "K narodu russkomu slovo o Russkoi Armii"; N. Savich; Lieut.-Gen. A von Lampe; P. Aleksinskii; Lieut.-Gen. I. KHolmnsen; I. Aleksinskii; B. Gershel'man; A. Guchkov; N. L'vov; A. Fedorov; Lieut.-Gen. P. Kondzerovskii on behalf of Grand Duke Nikolai Nikolaevich; newpaper clippings, mostly re monarchist politics: Novoe Vremia, Rodina, Posledniia Novosti, Vechernee Vremia, Ruskaia Gazeta, Dni, Rul', Rus', Russkaia Gazeta, Za Svobodu, Vozrozhdenie, Parizhskii Vestnik; Lieut.-Gen. A. Kutepov; translation of interview with Daily Telegraph: "Velikii Kniaz; Nikolai o budushchem Rossii..."; B. Gagarin re legitimist monarchist politics; N. Markov and Vysshii Monarkhicheskii Sovet; A. KHripunov and Vnepartiinoe Natsional'noe Ob"edinenie Russkikh v Germanii; Lieut.-Gen. V. SHtrandtman; Prince G. Leikhtenbergskii and Soiuz Ob"edinennykh Monarkhistov, includes printed party program; A. Trepov, includes speech given at Paris Conference,; S. Paleolog; N. CHebyshev; M. Domrachev and Komitet Monarkhicheskikh Organizatsii Dal'niago Vostoka, miscellaneous material; P. Dolgorukov; I. Il'in; V. SHul'gin; typescript and handwritten, December 20, 1924-January 7, 1926, September, 1925 (File File 41)
    Available on microfilm reel 196
  - Political correspondence, Vol. VII; Baron P. Vrangel', includes miscellaneous newspaper clippings re his move to Belgium; Lieut.-Gen. I. KHolmnsen; Lieut.-Gen. A. Lukomskii; Prince G. Leikhtenbergskii; P. Struve; newspaper clippings: Vozrozhdenie; anonymous: "Sovremennaia Rossiia (lichnyia vpechatleniia)"; C. Fricero; L. Semenovskii; V. SHul'gin; M. Domrachev and Komitet Monarkhicheskikh Organizatsii Dal'niago Vostoka; I. Uvarov, Petrogradskaia Ssudnaia Kazna and financing of Russian Army; N. CHebyshev; Lieut.-Gen. P. SHatilov; A. Tyrkova-Williams; Lieut.-Gen. E. Miller; V. Davats, Gody: clippings of reviews from miscellaneous newspapers; Soiuz Invalidov and General-of-Cavalry N. Baratov; S. Paleolog; I. Aleksinskii; V. Davats; newpaper clipping: L'Humanité (re Russian workers); Lieut.-Gen. von Lampe, includes miscellaneous material re "Kenkel Affair"; V. Malama, re "Legitimist" intrigues in Hungary; N. CHebyshev; A. Aleksinskii; newspaper clippings: miscellaneous material re Russkii Komitet S.KH.S.; Lieut.-Gen. A. Bogaevskii: open letter to Cossacks; typescript and handwritten, January 12-November 14, 1926 (Box 151, File File 42)
    Available on microfilm reel 198
  - Political correspondence, Vol. VIII; Baron P. Vrangel', includes miscellaneous newspaper clippings re Vrangel' and interviews with him; N. CHebyshev; I. Uvarov and financial matters; Lieut.-Gen. A. Lukomskii, Lieut.-Gen. A. Bogaevskii, Grand Duke Nikolai Nikolaevich and Cossacks; P. Struve; IU. Lodyzhenskii; S. Paleolog; I. Davats; S. Merkulov; Lieut.-Gen. A. von Lampe; A. Guchkov; Lieut.-Gen. E. Klimovich; A. Aleksinskii; N. Savich; V. SHul'gin; Prince G. Leikhtenbergskii; M. Domrachev and Komitet Monarkhicheskikh Organizatsii Dal'niago Vostoka; newspaper clippings re Russian fleet in Bizerte; Lieut.-Gen. I. KHolmnsen; Hungary: V. Malama, "Legitimist" intrigues, relations with Hungarian government and Vrangel''s visit; A. KHripunov; L. Semenovskii; typescript and handwritten, November 2, 1926-June 23, 1927 (File File 43)
  - Political correspondence, Vol. IX, Part II and increment "P.W. 6" containing additional correspondence of Baron P. Vrangel' re church schism, 1927-1928; Baron P. Vrangel'; Lieut.-Gen. A. von Lampe; N. CHebyshev; S. Paleolog; Lieut.-Gen. E. Klimovich; V. Davats; N. L'vov, includes clipping of speech re Prince P. Dolgorukov; A. Guchkov; L. Semenovskii; Kazach'e Ob"edinenie v g. SHankhae; "Trest," miscellaneous material, includes: "'Trest'. Vyderzhki iz pisem k Generalu ot Infanterii A.P. Kutepovu"; M. Volkov; A. Fedorov; V. SHul'gin; Illiustrirovannaia Rossiia: clippings re "Trest," Savinkov, Opperput, Reilly, Vrangel'; Rossia, clipping: "V.V. SHul'gin o Svoei poezdke v S.S.S.R."; V. Burtsev; Vozrozhdenie and other newspapers re "Trest" and V. SHul'gin... "Bratstvo Russkoi Pravdy": miscellaneous material, includes clippings and letters of "Georgii"; Prince G. Leikhtenbergskii; A. KHripunov; miscellaneous material re tenth anniversary of Soviet rule; Soviet exposition in Brussels: miscellaneous clippings; Mitropolit Antonii KHrapovitskii; L. Semenovskii; typescript and handwritten, July 1, 1927-April 14, 1928 (File File 44)
    Available on microfilm reel 199
  - Correspondence of Baron P. Vrangel' with foreigners and clippings from foreign newspapers; Major Takahashi (Japanese Military Mission in Constantinople); Admiral G. de Robeck; Sir C. Harrington; M. Horthy; C. Rivet; S. Hoare; Gen. Pelle; T. Aubert (Entente Internationale Contre la IIIe Internationale); C. Fricero; Lord S. Sydenham; Vice-Admiral L. Exelmans; J. Laroche; H. Williams; C. Huszar; G. Pachitch; deposition of Baron P. Vrangel' in case of "Herman Bernstein vs. Henry Ford and the Dearborn Publishing Co." (Baron P. Vrangel' and anti-Semitism); Gen. J. Percy; miscellaneous correspondence Vrangel' family (German branch); typescript and handwritten, March 39, 1921-April 23, 1928 (Box 152, File File 45)
    Available on microfilm reel 200
  - Miscellaneous correspondence; Baron P. Vrangel'; report re Gallipoli and Gen. of Infantry A. Kutepov; E. Balabanov; obituaries: S. Il'in and V. Nabokov; Mitropolit Antonii KHrapovitskii; P. Orlov; miscellaneous material: case of P. Persianov vs. Baron P. Vrangel'(Serbian Court); N. CHebyshev re D. Nikiforov affair; Lieut.-Gen. A. von Lampe; Baron A. Tiesenhausen and Russko-Slavianskii Bank; micellaneous material re building of Russian Church in Belgrade; W. Antonoff & A. Tchebycheff, Avocats Internationaux and attempts to instigate legal proceedings against Russian Army; typescript and handwritten, October 1, 1921-October 18, 1927 (File File 46)
    Available on microfilm reel 201
  - Personal correspondence as Commander-in-Chief; Baron P. Vrangel'; letter of condolence on death of A. Krivoshein and Gen. Pokrovskii; M. Girs; Lieut.-Gen. P. SHatilov; Lieut.-Gen. A. Lukomskii; Mitropolit Antonii KHrapovitskii; Prince G. Leikhtenbergskii; P. Rodzianko; Sovet Obshchestva popecheniia o dukhovnykh nuzhdakh...v S.KH.S.: protocol; Baron Vrangel' von Gubenthal re Nachertanie Zveria; P. Struve; Lieut.-Gen. A. von Lampe; N. CHebyshev; A. Trepov; Order No. 72, August 30, 1914, signed von Rennenkampf, awarding Baron P. Vrangel' St. George's Cross; V. Lekhovich; miscellaneous material re Battle of Kauschen; Lieut.-Gen. A. Kutepov; P. Krasnov; greetings from miscellaneous Russian emigre organizations, includes Soiuz Russkikh Inzhenerov (S. Verhovskoy), Rossiiskoe Obshchestvo Krasnago Kresta and others; publication of Vrangel's memoir: S. Krechetov and "Medny Wssadnik Verlag," The English Review; letters on occasion of illness,; typescript and handwritten, April 1, 1921-April 20, 1928, August 1928 (File File 47)
  - Decrees and orders of the Commander-in-Chief of the Russian Army, Baron P. Vrangel', typescript, handwritten and printed, November 6, 1920-April 7, 1928 (File File 48)
    Available on microfilm reel 202
  - Correspondence re publication of Beloe Delo, (Letopis' Beloi bor'by); Baron P. Vrangel'; Lieut.-Gen. A. von Lampe; Prince A. Lieven; L. Semenovskii; N. Savich; Prince G. Leikhtenbergskii; S. Paleolog; V. Davats: review of Beloe Delo, clipping; miscellaneous material, financing of publication; typescript, handwritten and printed matter, December 20, 1925-April 23, 1928 (Box 153, File File 49)
  - Sinking of the yacht "Lucullus," miscellaneous material, includes: report of official French investigation; corresponence re legal proceedings to recover damages; typescript and handwritten., October 31, 1921-June 17, 1926 (File File 51)
  - Finansovyi Sovet, minutes of meetings (zhurnal), No. typescript with holograph signatures, November 10, 1920-March 22, 1921, 1-36 (File File 52)
  - Minutes of meetings (zhurnaly), typescript (File File 53)
    Available on microfilm reel 203
    - Osobaia Likvidatsionnaia Komissiia, No., 1-5, November 1920
    - Khoziaistvenyi Komitet, No., 1-13, November-December 1920
    - Likvidatsionnaia Komissiia, No., 1-62, December 1920-June 1921
    - Podkomissiia po razsmotreniiu pretenzii, No., 1-56, December 1920-May 1921
  - Minutes of meetings (zhurnaly), typescript (File File 54)
    - Smetno-Raspredelitel'naia Komissiia, No. 6, 1921-1924, 1-10
    - Smetnoe Soveshchanie, No., 1-18, 1924-1925
  - Finansovo-Kontrol'nyi Komitet, minutes of meetings (zhurnaly), typescript, 1922-1925 (Box 154, File File 55)
    Available on microfilm reel 204
  - "Svodnyi otchet ob oborotakh summ, assignovannykh iz Voennago Fonda," typescript, September 1922-October 1924 (File File 56)
  - "Delo o prodazhe serebrianoi monety, dragotsennostei, zolotykh i serebriannykh veshchei," includes material re "Petrogradskaia Ssudnaia Kazna," typescript and handwritten, June 9, 1920-January 3, 1922 (File File 57)
    Available on microfilm reel 205
  - "Delo o prodazhe prosrochennykh zakladov Petrogradskoi Ssudnoi Kazny," typescript, October 14, 1921-January 15, 1925 (File File 58)
  - "Delo o peredache Petrogradskoi Ssudnoi Kazny v vedenie Ministerstva Finansov Korolevstva S.KH.S.," also includes newspaper clippings re transaction, typescript and printed matter, June 10, 1921-December 2, 1923 (Box 155, File File 59)
    Available on microfilm reel 206
  - Kantseliariia Glavnokomanduiushchago Russkoi Armii, miscellaneous material re transfer of Russian War Bonds to Lieut.-Gen. E. Miller, typescript and handwritten, May 16, 1925-March 29, 1926 (File File 60)
  - List of banners and other regalia placed in keeping of the Russian Church in Belgrade, includes photographs, January 23, 1926 (File File 61)
    Available on microfilm reel 207
  - "Kratkii ocherk deistvii flota pri evakuatsii Kryma v noiabre 1920 i prebyvanie ego na chuzhbine," includes maps indicating route of evacuation, typescript, July 27, 1923 (File File 62)
  - Sanitarnaia CHast' Russkoi Armii, "Otchet o deiatel'nosti Sanitarnoi CHasti Russkoi Armii v Konstantinopole" and "Compte-rendu de la Section de Santé du Service de Santé et de Secours aux Réfugiés Russes". Includes sketches of flags of Sanitary Section and graphs indicating frequency of various illnesses, typescript, November 1920-June 1921 (Box 156, File File 63)
  - "Russkaia Armiia na chuzhbine, ocherk sostavlennyi polkovn. Alatyrtsevym," typescript, 1920-1921 (File File 64)
    Available on microfilm reel 208
  - "Donskoi Korpus na o. Lemnose g.," typescript, 1921 (File File 65)
  - Reznichenko, S., "Russkaia Armiia v Bolgarii. Ocherk," typescript, Tyrnovo, 1922 (File File 66)
  - Vserossiiskii Zemskii Soiuz, "Biulleten' Vremennago Glavnago Komiteta," No. 1, typescript, June 1921 (File File 67)
  - Vserossiiskii Soiuz Gorodov: V.D. Kuzmin-Karavaev, "Vserossiiskii Soiuz Gorodov. Revizionnoe obsledovanie deiatel'nosti v Konstantinopol'skom raione," typescript, Constantinople, 1922
  - Kuzmin-Karavaev, V.D., "TSentral'nyi Ob"edinenyi Komitet Rossiiskago Obshchestva Krasnago Kresta, Vserossiiskago Zemskago Soiuza i Vserossiiskago Soiuza Gorodov. Revizionnoe obsledovanie del i otchetnosti po denezhnym operatsiiam," typescript, Constantinople, 1922 (File File 68)
  - Clippings, miscellaneous, mostly Russian emigre newspapers, March 19-December 3, 1921. Includes: Golos Rusi, Obshchee Delo, Le Gaulois, Novaia Russkaia ZHizn', Prikarpatskaia Rus', L'Humanité, Rul', La France de l'ouest, Novoe Vremia, Presse du soir, Posledniia Novosti, Volia Rossii (Box 157, File File 69)
    Available on microfilm reel 209
  - Clippings, Vera i Vrenost', August 25, 1923-February 16, 1925 (File File 70)
    Available on microfilm reel 210
  - Clippings, Staroe Vremia, October 8, 1923-September 28, 1924 (File File 71)
  - Clippings, Russkaia Gazeta, May 7, 1923-May 30, 1925 (Box 158, File File 72)
  - Clippings, Posleniia Novosti, March 7, 1923-March 8, 1926 (File File 73)
  - Printed matter. Vozrozhdenie, No. 7, June 3, 1925-August 18, 1927, 1-80 (File File 77-79)
    Not microfilmed
  - Reports, Russian Diplomatic Representative in the U.K., E. Sablin, "Osvedomitel'noe soobshchenie Gospodinu Starshmu Rossiiskomu Diplomaticheskomu Predstaviteliu zagranitsei," Vol. I, No. 123-200, typescript, March 3-June 6, 1922 (File File 80)
    Available on microfilm reel 211
  - Same as above, Vol. II, No. 201-300, July 6-September 29, 1922 (File File 81)
  - Same as above, Vol. III, No. 301-400, October 6, 1922-February 23, 1923 (Box 159, File File 82)
    Available on microfilm reel 212
  - Same as above, Vol. IV, No. 401-643, February 26-October 30, 1923 (File File 83)
    Available on microfilm reel 212A
  - Serbin, Col. IU., "Deistviia Kubanskikh Otriadov v kontse i nachale 1918 godov," typescript, Belgrade, 1926, 1917 (File File 84)
    Available on microfilm reel 213
  - SHtab Donskogo Korpusa, Kazaki za granizeiu, 1921-1925, printed copy (File File 89)
  - Davats, V. and L'vov, N., Russkaia Armiia na chuzhbine, Belgrade, 1923 (File File 90)
  - Russkaia Armiia v izgnanii 1920-1923, printed copy (File File 92)
  - Printed matter. Davats, V., Gody. Ocherki piatiletnei bor'by, 1926 (File File 93)
  - A.B.Off., Mémoire sur le mouvement communiste en Bulgarie durant les années 1921 et 1922, printed copy (File File 95)
  - ZHivym i gordym, Izdanie Obshchestva Gallipoliitsev, Belgrade, printed copy, 1923 (File File 97)
  - Printed matter. Dreier, V. von, Krestnyi put' vo imia Rodiny. Dvukhletniia voina krasnago severa s belym iugom. 1918-1920 (File File 102)
  - Popov, Maj.-Gen., Pravosudie v voiskakh Generala Vrangelia, printed copy, 1921 (File File 103)
  - Bykhovskii Al'bom, "Beloe Delo," printed copy, undated (File File 117)
  - Konichki Glasnik..., Belgrade, 1926 (File File 118)
  - Pamphlets
    - L'vov, N., Beloe Dvizhenie, printed copy, 1924 (Box 160:119, Folder 1)
    - Shmit, V. et al., "Otchet finansovo-kontrol'nago komiteta ob izrazkhodovanii summ, vyruchennykh t prodazhi prosrochennykh zakladov Petrogradskoi Ssudnoi Kazny," printed copy, undated (Folder 2)
    - Bolezn', smert' i pogrebenie...Petra Nikolaevicha Vrangelia v Briussele, Izdanie Soiuza Gallipoliitsev v Bel'gii, Brussels, 1928 (Folder 3)
    - Otechestvo, January 1927 (Folder 4)
  - Newspapers
    - Gallipoli, No. I and II (includes M. Tsvetaeva and V. Sirin poems), February 15 and April 8, 1923 (Folder 5)
    - Gallipoliets, No. I (includes A. Kuprin and I. SHmelev), 1927 (Folder 6)
    - Novoe Vremia, February 28, 1926 (Folder 7)
    - Pervopokhodnik, No. I, 1928 (Folder 8)